어서, 조이
Come on, Joey!
I told you everything I knew
last night.
레이첼, 내가 아는 건
어젯밤에 다 말했어
별것도 아니잖아
모니카랑 챈들러랑 한다고
It's not that big a deal.
So they're doing it.
어떻게 그런 식으로 말하니?
I cannot believe you would say that!
Sorry. Monica and Chandler
are "making love."
미안, 모니카랑 챈들러랑
사랑을 만들어가고 있어
No, I mean, come on.
This is a huge deal!
그게 아니라
너무 엄청난 사건이잖아
I need more details.
Who initiated the first kiss?
좀더 자세히 얘기해 봐
누가 먼저 첫 키스를 했니?
I don't know.
몰라
God, I just can't imagine Chandler
being romantic.
챈들러한테 그런 면이
있었다니 놀라워
같이 있을 때 로맨틱한가?
Is he romantic with her?
I don't know.
몰라
Are they in love?
두 사람 사랑에 빠졌어?
I don't know.
몰라
You don't know anything.
아는 게 없구만
I know one thing.
- 이건 안다
- 뭔데?
걔들 어제 저 소파에서 했어
They did it right there.
The One With Chandler's Work Laugh
- 어서 와, 로스
- 그래
스콘 하나만 줄래요?
Could I have a scone?
-Want to hear some good news?
-ls somebody else gonna give it to us?
희소식 하나 알려줘?
다른 사람이 발표해라
넌 없는 것 같으니까
Because you certainly don't seem like
you have any.
아냐, 있어
내가 아는 누가 결혼한대
No, I do.
Someone I know is getting married.
결혼이야 경사스런 일이지만
주인공이 내 전처 에밀리야
Weddings are happy occasions.
Oh, it's my ex-wife, Emily!
Sorry, man.
이걸 어쩌냐
-Here's your scone.
-Thanks.
스콘 나왔어
고마워요, 건터
고마워
Stupid British snack food!
거지같은 영국 빵!
Did they teach you that
in anger management?
성질 죽이기 강좌에서
그렇게 하라든?
좋은 방법을 가르쳐줄까?
이렇게 생각해봐
You know what might
help you deal with it?
You two are in the past.
You can't be mad about the past.
너와 에밀리는 과거에 있는 거야
과거지사는 화낼 이유가 없잖아
Are you still mad about, you know,
the Louisiana Purchase?
루이지애나 매입 건에 대해
아직도 화내는 사람 있어?
그건 화낼 일이 아니잖아
Nobody's mad about that.
거봐, 지나간 일이라 그렇지
Exactly!
Because it's in the past.
Anybody going to eat that?
저거 먹을 사람 없지?
Look at us all dressed up for the party.
What are we celebrating?
회사 파티라고
다들 잘 차려입었네
뭘 기념하는 거지?
크리스마스 파티 때
남은 술이 많아서
We had a lot of liquor
left over from Christmas.
Our friends aren't here. We can be
a real couple. We don't have to hide.
신난다, 아는 사람 없으니까
진짜 연인처럼 보여도 되잖아
이렇게 할 수도 있고
I know. I can do this.
And I can do this.
이것도 괜찮고
We can't do that.
- 이건 안 돼
- 안 될 말이지
어이, 빙!
Hey, Bing!
Who's the pretty lady,
and what is she doing with you?
이렇게 예쁜 아가씨는
자네랑 볼일이 없을 텐데?
I asked myself
that very question, sir.
저도 그게 궁금하던 참이죠
이쪽은 모니카입니다
My boss, Doug.
사장님이셔
모니카예요
-This is Monica.
-Hi.
안녕하세요?
반갑습니다
여긴 집사람 카라요
-This is my wife, Kara.
-Nice to meet you.
반가워요, 모니카
- 빙!
- 됐습니다
Did you hear about the new law firm
working for us?
새로 계약한 법률회사
이름이 뭔지 아나?
아뇨
'말아먹고 튀어라'
Dickem, Stickem & Run.
Let's go drink our body weight.
가서 진탕 마셔봅시다
What was that?
- 그게 뭐야?
- 뭐가?
- 방금 그 괴상한 소리
- 접대용 웃음이야
That noise you made?
Oh, my work laugh.
Your work laugh?
접대용 웃음?
이 파티에서 살아남으려면
자기도 하나쯤 준비해 둬
If you're going to survive this party,
come up with one too.
All right. Check me out.
- 좋아, 해볼게
- 그래
'30달러예요, 신부님
시내랑 똑같아요'
He says, "$30, Father.
Same as in town."
Everybody at work loved you last night.
회사 사람들 모두
널 아주 좋게 봤어
- 정말?
- 널 데려갔다고
And they like me more
just because I was with you.
나까지 예쁘게 봐
조이 때문에 실추됐던
내 체면이 회복됐어
You repaired the damage
from when they met Joey.
사장님이 테니스 한번 치재
밖에선 말도 안 거는 양반인데
Doug wants to play tennis.
He never talks to me outside of work.
Except for that time
at that strip club.
스트립클럽에서 우연히
만났을 때 빼고는
Strip church.
스트립 교회
-I'll go find a racket.
-I thought you had one.
- 라켓이나 준비해야겠다
- 하나 있잖아
있었는데 조이가 그걸로
돌을 쳐보자고 하는 통에...
I used to, but then Joey thought
it'd be fun to go hit rocks...
...at bigger rocks.
무지 큰 돌
너 테니스 라켓 있니?
Do you have a tennis racket?
조이한테 빌려줬는데
아직 못 받았어
I lent it to Joey, and
I've never gotten it back.
Good luck with that.
무사하길 빈다
- 여기 있었네?
- 그래
What's up?
뭐하고 있었어?
Why are you here?
I thought you had inventory.
이 시간에 웬일이야?
종일 재고 정리한다며
느긋하게 점심 먹고 내 친구
모니카나 좀 보려고 나왔지
I do, but I decided I'd take
a long lunch...
...and spend some time
with my friend Monica.
You know, I feel like
we don't talk anymore.
요즘 우리 대화가 너무 부족해
How are you?
어떻게 지내?
소식 좀 전하고 살자
What is new with you?
Not much. Work's good.
별일 없어
일도 재미있고
일 얘기 아니라도 돼
무슨 얘기든 다 좋아
We don't have to talk about work.
Talk about anything.
좋아
참! 이럴 게 아니라
남자 얘기나 하자
You know what?
Let's talk about relationships.
- 좋아, 너 무슨 일 있구나
- 전혀
What's going on?
Nothing.
You go.
네 차례야
There was this guy at the bank
that I thought was cute.
은행에 근사한
남자가 있었는데
But I don't anymore.
지금은 시들해
That's juicy.
와, 그거 참 재미있다
You know what? I actually do
have a lot of work to do.
그런데 실은 나
할 일 무지 많거든
- 정말 다른 얘기는 없어?
- 그렇다니까
You're sure there's just
not anything else?
I'm sure. Is there something
you want to talk to me about?
- 나한테 할 얘기 있니?
- 아니
No!
그게...
있어도 너한텐 말 안 해
If there was, I wouldn't tell you.
Then what happened?
그래서 어떻게 됐는데?
You'll get your turn.
넌 조금 있다 나서
- 피비, 뭐하니?
- 아무 것도
-Hey, Phoebe. What's going on?
-Nothing.
This is not over.
이따 얘기하자
No, no, no!
- 이런...
- 왜?
I was up all night writing
this nasty letter to Emily.
밤새 에밀리 원망하는
내용의 편지를 써놨는데
It was perfect,
and now it's all covered in....
이 녀석들이 온통...
Actually, thanks!
뭐 잘했다
All right!
Ready to go to the movies?
이제 영화 보러 가야지?
Actually, I think I'll skip it.
- 난 그냥 빠지고 싶다
- 진짜?
Really?
집에서 책이나 읽을래
혼자 있고 싶어
I'll read my book.
I just want to be alone right now.
Sure you don't want to?
정말 안 갈 거야?
Tom Hanks, Meg Ryan.
They get mail and stuff.
톰 행크스, 멕 라이언 주연의
메일 어쩌고 하는 영화래
That's okay, Joe.
됐어
좋을 대로
가자, 피비
Let's go, Phoebe.
윽! 으엑!
빙!
끝났죠?
Game!
I got to tell you, that partner
of yours is a real tiger.
빙, 자네 파트너
무시무시하군
당신 괜찮아?
Are you all right?
We'll just get
a little sip of water.
물 한 모금 마시고 하지
Am I on fire today or what?
오늘 내 라켓에 불붙었다
Those birds are browned,
basted and ready to be carved.
잘 튀겨진 통닭 두 마리
이제 칼질만 해주세요
진정해, 마르티나 힝기스
Okay, easy, Martina.
I think we should let them
win the next game.
다음 게임은 져드리자고
I'm sorry, I don't understand
what you just said.
뭐? 그게 무슨 뜻이야?
Let them win one.
- 한 게임 져드려
- 돌았어?
Are you crazy? We own those two.
Look at them!
우리가 한수 위야
저걸 봐
He can't even breathe,
and she's popping pills.
사장님은 숨도 못 쉬고
사모님은 약 털어 넣고
You're not giving them a chance.
넌 아예 기회도 안 주잖아
저쪽은 맨손으로 치나?
They have rackets.
빙, 이번 게임으로 끝내지
We'll make this the last game.
Yes, sir. Put me out of my misery.
좋습니다, 이제야 살겠군요
정말 프로로 뛴 적 없으세요?
Are you sure you never played pro?
Please let them win.
제발 져드리자
I'll take it down to 95%,
but that's the best I can do.
내 실력의 95%만 발휘할게
그 이하로는 안 돼
-Missed it!
-I got it!
- 아이쿠, 놓쳤네
- 내가 받았어
Nice shot.
나이스 샷!
I got it!
내가 받을게!
길다!
Long!
I can't believe you let them win.
일부러 져주는 게 어디 있어!
그렇다고 꼭 이렇게
티를 내야겠어?
Well, at least you hid
your feelings well about it.
I was frustrated.
- 화나는 걸 어떡해
- 내 라켓이야
It's my racket.
너한테 화났으니까
Frustrated with you!
If we hadn't lost, they would never have
invited us to dinner tomorrow.
우리가 이겼으면
저녁 초대도 못 받았어
What bothers me...
정말 속상한다
...is how different
you act around them.
사장님 부부 앞에선
완전히 딴사람이야
The throwing the tennis games,
the fake laugh...
테니스게임 져주고
맘에도 없는 웃음에
...the "See you later, Bing!"
"Not if I see you first, Doug!"
'그럼 다음에 보세, 빙'
'제가 먼저 뵐 겁니다'
Listen, I don't sound
like some crazed, drunken pirate.
내가 무슨 술 취한
미치광이 해적이야?
I know you don't,
but "work Chandler" does.
평상시엔 아니지만
접대용 챈들러는 그래
I don't like work Chandler.
The guy's a suck-up.
접대용 챈들러
정말 재수 없어
Because you said that...
그래, 말 한번 잘했다
...I'm not putting out tonight!
오늘밤엔 나도 안 해
뭐가 잘못된 게 분명해
오빤 외박할 사람이 아냐
Something's wrong.
My brother doesn't stay out all night.
Maybe we should check
the trash chute.
쓰레기 비우는 데 찾아볼까?
Ross couldn't fit
down the trash chute.
로스가 거기 들어가나?
아슬아슬하게 맞을 걸
That's right. He almost could.
Which is exactly
how I got stuck there.
그래서 나도 끼었잖아
- 왔네
- 어서 와
세상에...
Oh, my God!
Where the hell have you been?
대체 어디 갔었어!
그냥 밖에
Just, you know, out.
저런, 밖에? 우리가 왜
거긴 안 찾아봤을까?
Oh, out! God, I don't know
why we didn't think to check there.
밖에서 뭐했어?
What were you doing?
술집에도 가고, 뭐...
I went to a bar, and then...
그냥 여기저기 돌아다녔어
...I just walked around for a while.
You walked around all night
in the city by yourself?
밤새 혼자서 시내를
돌아다녔단 말이야?
He hooked up!
혼자가 아냐
He hooked up.
누구랑 같이 있었어
대답하고 싶지 않아
난 성인이라고
I don't have to answer your questions.
I'm a big boy.
I can do what I want.
- 뭘 하든 내 자유야
- 혼자가 아니었어
He hooked up!
Tell us about her!
누군지 빨리 불어
Ross, you left your scarf
로스, 스카프 두고 갔어...
Hey, you guys.
다들 반가워요
그래요, 알았어요
I know what you all are thinking,
but Chandler is in Yemen.
무슨 생각하는지 알지만
챈들러는 예멘에 있잖아요
I'm a young woman. I have needs.
I can't wait forever.
난 아직 젊은데
무한정 기다릴 순 없어요
Yeah, that's what I was thinking.
네, 그럴 거라 짐작했어요
So I'm asking you, please,
just take a moment before you judge me.
부탁인데 무작정 날
비난하진 말아줘요
그쪽을 비난하진 않아요
Nobody's judging you.
좋아요, 그대
가뭄에 단비 같은 사나이!
Mr. Right-place-at-the-right-time...
...call me.
연락해요
So I guess you finished your book.
어쨌든 독서를 마치셨군
그럼 대화할 시간 있겠네?
Had some time on our hands, did we?
I know what you guys are going to say.
무슨 말하려는지 알아
두 사람 애 낳으면
털 무지 많겠다
You two would have
very hairy children.
I didn't know you'd say that.
그 말은 뜻밖이네
로스, 재니스라니!
Ross! Janice?
다들 진정하시고
All right. Hold on, hold on.
This is Ross.
얜 로스야
우리 친구라고
He's our friend.
He obviously went crazy.
머리가 어떻게 됐어
완전히 돌아버린 거지
He obviously lost his mind.
Look, it's not that crazy. Okay?
그게 그렇게 놀랄 일인가?
But it's Janice! I mean, she's...
하지만 재니스야
그니까...
...Janice!
재니스라고!
How drunk were you?
약 먹었어?
Janice and I have a lot in common.
재니스와 난 공통점이 많아
We've both been divorced.
We both have kids.
둘 다 이혼경험이 있고
아이도 있어
그래서 다시 만나겠다고?
Are you going to see her again?
어허, 말이 씨 된다니까
-Don't put ideas in his head!
-I will see her.
- 다시 만날 거야
- 거봐, 어쩔래
Damn it, Phoebe!
I have to tell you something
that I've never admitted.
그동안 꼭꼭 숨겨왔던 거
사실대로 털어놓을게
In high school, I made out with James
even though I knew you liked him.
고교 때 나 제임스랑 만났어
네가 좋아하는 줄 알면서도
와! 속이 다 시원하네
이제 네 차례야
That feels so good to get off my chest.
Okay, you go.
My turn? What are you talking about?
내 차례라니, 무슨 소리야?
모니카...
I know about you and Chandler.
너랑 챈들러 일 알고 있어
뭐?
I overheard you
on the phone the other day.
너희들 통화할 때 들었는데
네가 이랬잖아
You said, "I'll tell Rachel I'm doing
laundry for a couple of hours."
'레이첼한테는 몇 시간
빨래한다고 둘러댈게'
And he said, "Laundry?
Is that my new nickname?"
그니까 챈들러 왈
'빨래? 그건 내 별명인가?'
And you said:
그러자 넌 '아니, 자기 별명
알잖아, 미스터 왕... '
"You know what
your nickname is, Mr. Big."
You're writing yourself
a little play there, Rach.
너 아주 소설을 쓰는구나
Let me know how it turns out.
나중에 결말이나 알려줘
I wouldn't know, because I got
so freaked out I hung up the phone.
난 몰라, 너무 놀라서
전화를 끊어버렸거든
Well, if you had kept listening...
끝까지 듣지 그랬어
...you would have heard me
call him Mister...
이렇게 결말이 났는데
미스터 왕...
...Bigot.
밥맛
- 뭐?
- 미스터 왕 밥맛
Mr. Bigot.
인종차별적인 농담은
도맡아서 하잖아
He tells the most racist jokes.
All right. So that's it.
알았어, 그 뿐이야?
There's nothing going on
between you and Chandler?
너랑 챈들러 사이에
아무 일도 없단 말이지?
Me and Chandler?
나하고 챈들러가?
- 자, 20달러 걸어
- 알았어
Put your $20 down.
First one to find
the tasty treat wins, okay?
먼저 맛있는 거 찾는
쪽이 이긴다, 알았지?
All right, let's get the contestants
out of their isolation booths.
좋아, 선수들은
부스에서 나와주세요
And they're off!
출발
우리 편 막지 마
Get your foot off my contestant!
Judge?
판정 결과는...
반칙 아니네요
Judge rules, no violation.
얘들아
어서 와
이런 말 이상하게 들리겠지만
오늘 제니스랑 정말 즐거웠어
It's so weird to say this,
but I just had a great date with Janice.
- 뭐?
- 정말이야?
-What?
-Are you serious?
그래
I opened up to her about all
the stuff that's been happening to me.
그간 내게 있었던 끔찍한
일들을 전부 털어놨어
몇 시간 동안이나!
놀랍지 않아?
I mean, I talked for hours.
It is amazing...
내 말을 그렇게 진지하게
들어주는 사람이 있다니
...to have someone give you
such focused attention.
You don't need Janice for that.
You've got us.
우리가 있는데
재니스가 왜 필요해?
- 오리가 버터 찾았다!
- 안 돼!
The duck gets the Nutter Butter!
That's not a Nutter Butter.
That's an old won ton!
저건 버터가 아니라
말라붙은 튀김이야
Judge rules...
판정 들어갑니다
...Nutter Butter.
버터 맞아
Tough call.
- 힘든 판정이었어
- 그래
Seriously, I strongly believe that
we should support President Clinton...
진심이야
우리로선 클린턴 대통령을
적극적으로 지지해야지
...and her husband, Bill.
남편으로서의 빌도
How do you like your coffee?
커피 어떻게 마셔요?
- 전 됐어요
- 전 설탕만 조금
-None for me.
-A little sugar.
모니카 손가락만 살짝 담가
그럼 달콤해질 테니까
I'll have Monica stick her finger in it.
That will sweeten it up.
-That laugh doesn't give you a headache?
-You get used to it.
- 그렇게 웃고도 머리 안 아파?
- 익숙해지면 괜찮아
I don't think that I can.
난 아무래도 안 되겠으니까
앞으로 이런 모임에선 빼 줘
This will be it for me
on the work things.
사장님 농담 듣고
웃은 것도 잘못됐어?
I laugh at my boss's jokes.
What's the big deal?
I'd rather not be with
this work-weasel guy...
난 콧소리 내는 아첨꾼보다
듬직한 남자친구가 좋더라
...when I can be with my boyfriend,
who I actually respect.
I got to apologize for Kara's coffee.
I'd feel sorry for it in a fight.
마누라 커피는 너무 순해
싸움에 안 나간 게 다행이지
죽도록 얻어터질 텐데
It's not strong enough
to defend itself.
Hear what I said?
내 말 못 들었나?
What?
네?
It's a joke.
What's the matter with you?
내 농담 말일세
왜 그러나?
- 별로 우습지 않은데요
- 뭐라고?
Well, I just didn't think
it was funny, sir.
Excuse me?
-Well, I just
-Honey?
- 제 생각엔...
- 자기야?
I just don't think
you understood the joke.
사장님 말씀을 이해 못했네
Really?
- 진짜?
- 그래...
I mean, it was really funny.
I just don't think that you got it.
정말 재미있는데
왜 모를까?
사모님 커피가 순하니까
You see, Kara's coffee
is weak-tasting.
But what Doug did was imply
that it was weak physically.
사람 성격이 순하다고
빗대서 말씀하졌잖아
-You get it now, honey?
-I think I do!
- 이제 알았어?
- 그런 것 같네
- 고마워, 모니카
- 꼭 찔러줘야 안다니까
-Thank you, Monica.
-I thought you could use the help.
Coffee in a fight!
커피가 싸움을 하다니
레이첼
You mind if I read
my comic books in here?
나 여기서 만화책 봐도 돼?
Sure. Why?
그래, 왜?
챈들러랑 모니카가 우리 집에
있어서 집중이 안 돼
Chandler and Monica are over there.
It's kind of hard to concentrate.
She just called and said
she was going to be working late.
뭐? 모니카는 방금
야근한다고 전화했는데
계속 거짓말을 하시겠다?
더는 못 참아
She keeps lying to me.
That's it! I'm going over there
and confronting them right now.
당장 가서 범행현장을
붙잡을 거야
Panty raid.
나갔다!
All right, so you're telling me
that I have to tell racist jokes now?
그러니까 이제 나더러
인종차별까지 하라고?
I'm just not very good at this.
미안해, 그렇게 됐어
원래 거짓말도 못하는데
상대가 레이첼이다 보니
I'm a terrible liar.
I hate having to lie to Rachel.
- 아직 털어놓긴 일러
- 알아
-But we're not ready to tell yet.
-I know.
Ever since high school, Rachel was the
one person that I told everything to.
고교시절부터 레이첼은 모든 걸
털어놓을 수 있는 유일한 애거든
지금도 그러고 싶어
I miss that so much now.
She's my best friend.
둘도 없는 친구니까
조이?
Oh, my God, Rachel!
- 맙소사, 레이첼
- 안녕? 반갑다
What are you doing here?
너 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
Well, I actually came over here
to borrow this lamp...
저기, 이 램프 좀
빌려갈까 하고
...to look at my books.
책 좀 읽게
더 잘 보이잖아
You know, see them a little better.
Okay, great.
알았어, 그랬구나
Well, what I was doing
in Chandler's room is that...
난 챈들러 방에서
뭘 하고 있었냐면...
...I was cleaning it.
청소하는 중이야
He pays me to clean it.
사실 돈 받고 하거든
What a great way to make
some extra pocket money.
용돈 벌기엔 괜찮은 부업이다
When I said to you earlier
that I was at work...
아까 야근한다고 말한 건...
...I'm at my new work.
부업도 일이잖아
Good enough. Right?
말 된다, 그래
난 이제...
I'll go look at my books.
가서 책 읽을게
- 알았어
- 그래
Go get back to my new job.
난 하던 일 마저 끝내고
그래
Congratulations on your new job!
부업 잘 구했다
Man, she is really gullible.
쟤 너무 잘 속는다
여기
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
고마워요
-Actually, I should get going.
-You're sure?
그만 갈게요
정말요? 원한다면
밤새도록 있을 수 있어요
I can stay out as late as you want.
I told you I'm on
sabbatical from work
- 내가 휴직 당한 얘기는 했죠?
- 네, 들었어요
Yes, yes. You did.
-Oh, man!
-What is wrong now?
- 이런...
- 또 뭐가 잘못됐죠?
This isn't what I ordered.
주문한 게 아니에요
Man! Can't anything
go right in my life?
내 인생은 왜 이리
꼬이기만 하지?
First, my marriage falls apart,
and then
결혼은 파탄 나고
다음엔...
I know!
알아요, 집에서 쫓겨나고
강제로 휴직 당하고
You lose your apartment,
you lose your job...
...your ex-wife gets married so fast!
And now the coffee!
전처는 부리나케 재혼하고
게다가 커피까지, 으악!
로스! 우리 얘기 좀 해요
We need to talk.
좋아요
-Sometimes I feel
-No, no, don't.
- 가끔 난...
- 아뇨, 그게 아니고
내가 얘기할게요
I'm going to talk.
I believe...
아무래도 날이 저문 것 같아요
우리의 화장하던 대낮이요
...that the sun has set...
...on our day in the sun.
네?
You're a very sweet person, Ross.
당신은 좋은 사람이지만...
Unfortunately...
안타깝게도 난 더 이상 당신
우는소리를 못 들어주겠어요
...I just don't think I can take
another second of you whining!
Let me make sure
I'm hearing this right.
그러니까 지금 그 말은...
You're ending this with me because...
나랑 끝내자는 건가요?
이유는 내가 너무 징징대서?
...I'm too whiny?
So you're saying...
다시 정리하면 내가
너무 징징대는 통에
...I've become so whiny...
...that l...
내가 아닌 제니스,
당신이 짜증난다
...annoy you...
...Janice.
네, 그래요
Well, yeah!
Oh, my God!
사람 환장하겠네
Will you be okay?
- 괜찮겠어요?
- 이제 멀쩡해요
I am now.
알았어요
- 안녕
- 왔어요?
저기...
I guess that's two out of three...
셋에서 둘 빼면 하나 남네
...Joey!
조이
Dude, we got to talk.
- 할 얘기가 있어
- 그래
다른 데서 듣기 전에
내가 말하는 게 좋겠어
I wanted to tell you something before
you heard it from someone else.
I hope this isn't too weird, but...
이상하게 들리겠지만...
...I had a thing with Janice.
나 제니스랑 사고 쳤어
You're not mad?
화 안 나?
Why would I be mad?
왜 화를 내겠어?
Because there's certain rules
about this kind of stuff.
이런 일엔 불문율
같은 게 있잖아
You don't fool around with
your friends' ex-girlfriends...
친구의 옛 애인은
안 된다든가
...or possible girlfriends
or girls they're related to.
친구가 찜한 여자나
친구의 가족도 그렇고
I am mad.
나 화났다
But you know,
I'm going to forgive you.
그럼에도 불구하고
널 용서하겠어
Because that's what friends do.
그게 우정이니까
They forgive their friends when
they do everything you just said.
방금 말한 그런 짓을 다 해도
용서하는 게 바로 우정이야
Thank you.
- 고맙다
- 하지만 이건 꼭 기억해
But I want you to remember...
...that I forgave you.
이번에 내가 너 용서한 거
- 알았어
- 이것도 명심해
I also want you to remember
that I let you live here rent-free.
우리 집에 공짜로
있게 해준 거
All right.
그래
또 이것도 잊지 마
And I want you to remember
that I gave you...
내가 너한테 27달러 준 사실
...twenty-seven dollars.
절대 다른 뜻은 없어
No strings attached!
If you can't remember that...
혹시 잊어버릴 수도 있으니까
장부에 적어놓는 게 좋겠다
...we should write it down.
Let's write it down!